let's solve this differentiation problem
step by step using the quotient rule we
need to differentiate the function f of
T = 1 + t + T ^2 / 1 - t + T ^2 let's
recall the quotient rule the derivative
of U over V equal V * DDT minus U *
dvdt all over V ^2 first let's identify
u and v here U equal 1 + t + T ^2 and V
= 1 - t + T ^2 next we need to find do
DT and dvdt the derivative of U is 1 +
2T and the derivative of V is - 1 + 2T
now let's substitute everything into the
quotient rule formula we get 1 - t + T
^2 * 1 + 2T - 1 + t + t^ 2 * - 1 + 2T
all over 1 - t + t^ 2^ 2 let's expand
the numerator first let's multiply 1 - t
+ T ^ 2 by 1 + 2T this gives us 1 + 2 t
- t - 2 T ^2 + T ^ 2 + 2 T Cub which
simplifies to 1 + t + 2 t^ 2 - 2 T Cub
now for the second part let's multiply 1
+ t + T ^2 by -1 + 2T this gives us -1 +
t - 3T ^2 + 2 T cubed now we can
subtract these Expressions 1 + t + 2 T
^2 - 2 T Cub - -1 + t - 3 T ^2 + 2 T Cub
this simplifies to 2 - 2 T ^2 therefore
our final answer is 2 *
1 - t ^ 2/ 1 - t + T ^ 2^ 2 and that's
how we use the quotient rule to
differentiate this rational function